When I've been building applications
with large language models,
I don't think I've ever come to the prompt
that I ended up using in
the final application on my first attempt.
And this isn't what matters.
As long as you have a good process
to iteratively make your prompt better,
then you'll be able to come to
something that works
well for the task you want to achieve.
You may have heard me say that
when I tried the machine learning model,
it almost never works the first time.
In fact, I'm very surprised
that the first molded train works
I think, were prompting the odds of it
working.
The first time is
maybe a little bit higher,
but as is the same doesn't matter
if the first plug works.
What matters most?
The process for getting to problems
that works through your application.
So with that, let's jump into the code
and let me show you some frameworks
to think about
how to iteratively develop a product.
So if you've taken a machine
learning course with me before,
you may have seen me use a diagram saying
that with machine learning development,
you often have an idea
and then implement it.
So right, get the data, train your model
and that gives you an experimental result.
And you can then look at that output,
maybe do error analysis, figure out
where is working or not working,
and then maybe even change your idea
of exactly what problem
you want to solve or how to approach it
and then change implementation
and run another experiment and so on.
Iterate over and over to get an effective
machine learning model.
If you're not familiar with machine
learning and hasn't seen this diagram
before, thought about it.
Not that important
for the rest of this presentation.
But when you are writing prompts
to develop an application using an own,
the process can be quite similar
where you have an idea for what you want
to do, the task you want to complete,
and you can then take a first attempt
at writing a prompt.
Then hopefully it's clear and specific
and maybe,
if appropriate, gives the system
time to think
and then you can run it
and see what result you get.
And if it doesn't work well
and not the first time,
then the iterative process of figuring out
why the instructions, for example,
were not clear enough or why it didn't
give the algorithm enough time to think
allows you to refine the idea,
ever find a prompts and so on.
And to go around this loop multiple times
until you end up with a prompt
that works for your application.
This too is why I personally have not paid
as much attention to the articles
that say throw perfect problems,
because I think there
probably isn't a perfect prompt
for everything under the sun is more
important is you have a process
for developing a good prompt
for your specific application.
So let's
look at the example together in code.
I have here the starter code that you saw
in the previous video
and I have important opening I those here
we get the opening AI API key
and this is the same helper function
that you saw as last time and
I'm going to use
as the running example in this video,
the task of summarizing
a fact sheet for a chair.
So let me just pay silence here
and feel free to pause the video
and read this more carefully
in the notebook on the left if you want.
But here's a fact sheet for a chair
with a description saying
as part of a beautiful family
of mid-century inspired and so on.
On top of all the construction
as the dimensions
options for the chair materials
and so on comes from similarly
So let's say you
want to take this fact sheet
and help a marketing team
write the description for a online
retail website.
Let me just quickly run these three
and then we'll come up with a prompt
as follows.
And I just and I'll just pieces in.
So my prompt here says Your task
is to help a marketing team
create instruction for a retail website,
a product based on a technology
ready product description and so on.
Right.
So this is my first attempt to explain
to task two, the launch language model.
So Limb chef enter and just takes
a few seconds to run
and we get this result.
It looks like it's done a nice job
writing a description, introducing
a semi mid-century inspired office chair,
Perfect Edition and so on.
But when lackadaisical boy,
this is really long.
It's done a nice job
doing exactly what that answer to,
which is start from the technical fact
sheet and write a product description.
But when I look at this, I go
just kind of long maybe we want it
to be a little bit shorter.
So I have had an idea.
I wrote a prompt, got a result.
I'm not too happy with it
because it's too long, so I will then
clarify my prompt
and say
Use has almost 50 words
to try to give better guidance
on the design line for this.
And let's run it again.
Okay.
To such you looks like a much nicer short
description of the product
introducing a mid-century
inspired office chair and so on.
Five for you
just yeah both stylish and practical.
Not bad
and I'd let me double check the length
that this is so good.
The take the response
split it quite to where the spaces
and then your prints are the length.
So 52 was actually not that
large
language models are okay,
but not that great.
And following instructions
about a very precise word count,
but this is actually not that sometimes
they'll print out something with 60 or 65
and so on words,
but it's kind of within reason.
Some of the things you could try to do
would be to say,
use that most the three sentences
and then we run that again.
But these are different ways
to tell the large language model
was the length of the output
that you want.
So to assess 1 to 3,
I can't see sentences
also that did a pretty good job on.
And then I've also seen people
sometimes do things like,
Oh no, you said most 280 characters,
a lot of language models
because of the way they interpret
texts using something called a tokenize,
which which I won't talk about,
but they tend to be so,
so a counting characters. But
let's
see, 281 cards is actually surprising
because usually a large language
model doesn't get it quite as close.
That is the different ways
they can play with to try to control
the length of the output that you get,
but then just switch it back to use
that most 50 words.
And as a result that we had just now,
as we continue
to refine this text for our websites,
we might decide that, boy,
this website isn't selling direct to
consumers is actually intended
to sell furniture to furniture retailers
that would be more interested
in the technical details of the chair
and the materials of the chair.
In that case, you can take this problem
and say, I want to modify this font
to get it to be more precise
about the technical details.
So let me keep on modifying this prompt,
and I'm going to say
this description is intended
for furniture retailers,
so should be technical and focus
the materials products and the it from
oh oh this one that
and let's see
not bad says, you know kota
aluminum bass and pneumatic chair,
high quality materials.
So by changing the prompts,
you can get it to focus more on specific
characters, on specific characteristics
you wanted to
and when I look at this,
I might decide
at the end of the description.
I also wanted
to include the product ideas.
So the two offerings of this chair
a surface you want in ac1 hundred.
So maybe I can further
improve this promise
and to get it to give me the product, it's
I can add this instruction
at the end of the description, include
every seven character from the idea
and the technical specification design
and let's run it and see what happens.
And so
says Inch, these are the sections
five Office chair, shell colors, textile
plastic coating aluminum base practical
some options
tossed about the two product
itis so just looks pretty good
and what you've just seen is shot
example of the areas of prompt development
that many developers will go through
and I think I guidelines
is in the last video
you saw user
share a number of best practices
and so what I usually do
is keep best practices like that.
It might be clear and specific and if
necessary, give the model time to think.
With those in mind.
It's worthwhile to often
take a first attempt at writing a problem,
see what happens, and then go from there
to iteratively refine
the prompt to get closer
and closer to the results that you need.
And so
a lot of the successful prompts
that you may see used in various
programs was arrive at iterative process
like this.
Just for fun, let me show you an example
of an even more complex problem
that might give you a sense of what's
catch ABC can do, which is I've just added
a few extra instructions here.
After description include the table,
the use of product dimensions,
and then your format. Everything is HTML.
So let's run that
and in practice
you end up with a prompt like this.
Really only after multiple innovations.
I don't think I know anyone
that would write this exact prompt.
The first time they were trying
to get the system to process a fact sheet.
And so this actually outputs
a bunch of the HTML.
Let's display the HTML to see
if this is even valid
and see if this works.
And I don't actually know
what's going to work.
Let's see. Oh, cool.
All right. Let's do the render it.
So it has this really nice
looking description of a chair
on construction materials,
product dimensions on.
Oh, it looks like I left out
the use in most 50 words instruction.
So it is a little bit long,
but if you want that, you can even
feel free to pause the video,
tell it to be more succinct, then
regenerate this
and see what results you get.
So I hope you took away from this video.
That prompt development
is an iterative process.
Try something, see how it does
not yet fulfill exactly what you want
and then think about how to clarify
your instructions or in some cases
think about how to give it more space.
So think to get it closer
to delivering the results that you want.
And I think the key
to being an effective engineer
isn't so much about knowing the perfect
front is about having a good process
to develop prompts
that are effective for your application.
And in this video
I illustrated developing a prompt using
just one example
for more sophisticated applications.
Sometimes you have multiple examples
say a list of ten or even 50
or 100 fact sheets and iteratively
develop a prompt evaluated a case,
a large set of cases.
But for the early development
of most applications, I see many people
developing it sort of the way
I am with just one example.
But then for more mature applications,
sometimes it could be useful
to evaluate prompts
against a larger set of examples,
such as to test different problems
on dozens of fact sheets
to see how is average or worst case
performance is on multiple fact sheets.
But usually you end up doing that
only when an application is more mature
and you have to have those metrics
to drive that incremental loss.
Your sense of prompt improvement.
So with that,
please to play with the duplicate notebook
examples and trial different variations
and see what results you get
and when you're done.
Let's go on to the next video.
We will talk about one very common
use of large language
models in software applications,
which is to summarize sex.
So when you're ready, let's
go on to the next video.