Welcome to
this course on
catch up from engineering for developers
are thrilled to have with me
is a full fit to teach this along with me
She's a member of the technical staff
of Openai and had built the popular chip
retrieval plugin, and a large
part of the work has been teaching people
how to use l M or large language
model technology in products.
She's also a contributor to the Open,
a cookbook that teaches people prompting.
So thrilled to have you with you
and I'm thrilled to be here and share
some prompting best practices
with you all.
So there's been a lot of material
on the internet for prompting
with articles like 30 prompts
everyone has to do.
A lot of that has been focused
on the chat Jupiter Web user interface,
which many people are using to do specific
and often one off tasks.
But I think the power of our like language
models as a developer to
that is using API calls to OEMs to quickly
build software applications.
I think that is still very
underappreciated.
In fact, my team at A.I.
Fund, which is a sister company
to deep A.I., has been working
with many startups
on applying these technologies
to many different applications,
and it's been exciting to see
what APIs can enable developers
to very quickly build.
So in this course, we'll share with you
some of the possibilities for what
you can do as well as best practices
for how you can do them.
There's a lot of material to cover fast.
You'll learn best, some prompting
best practices for software development
that will cover some common use cases
summarizing, inferring,
transforming, expanding.
And then you'll build a chatbot
using an Al-Alam.
We hope that
this will spark your imagination
about new applications that you can build.
So in the development of large language
models, OEMs have been broadly two types
of of which I'm going to refer to as base
and instruction tunes elements.
So Basil has been trained
to predict the next words
based on text training data, often
trained on large amount of data
from the Internet and other sources
to figure out what's the next
most likely word to follow.
So, for example,
if you were to prompt this,
once upon a time there was a unicorn,
it may complete.
This does is it
may predict the next several words
are that live in the magical forest
of all unicorn friends.
But if you
were to prompt us with
what is the capital of France, then
based on what articles on the internet
might have is quite possible to the base,
our team will complete this
with what is France's largest city,
what is France's population, and so on,
because articles on the internet
could quite plausibly be lists of quiz
questions about the country of France.
In contrast, an instruction tuned out,
which is where a lot of momentum
of research and practice has been going
and instruction
has been trained to follow instructions.
So if you were to ask
what is the capital of France is much
more likely to output
something like two cups of France's Paris.
So the way that instruction tune
owners are typically trained
is you start off with a base, doesn't
train the huge amount of text data
and further train it further
fine, tune it within present outputs
the instructions and good attempts
to follow those instructions
and then often further refined
using a technique called HSF reinforcement
learning from human feedback
to make the system better,
able to be helpful and follow instructions
because instructions
have been trained
to be helpful on this and home this.
So for example,
they're less likely to output problematic
text such as toxic outputs
compared to base alarm.
A lot of the practical usage scenarios
have been shifting to other instructions.
You know, as some of the best practices
you find on the Internet
may be more suited for a base element.
But for most practical applications today,
we would recommend most people instead
focus on instruction to use ohms,
which are easier to use,
and also because of the work of Open the
I and other companies
becoming safer and more aligned.
So this
course will focus on best practices
for instruction to our homes,
which is what we recommend
you use for most of your applications.
Before moving on,
I just want to acknowledge the team
from opening and Deployment II
that had contributed to the materials
that is in I will be presenting.
I'm very grateful to Andrew Main, Joe
Palermo, Boris
Power,
Ted Sanders and Lily Wang from Open Air.
They were very involved
with us, brainstorming materials,
vetting the materials to put together
the curriculum for this short course.
And I'm also grateful for the tip
learning site for the work of Jeff
Ludwig at issue and Tony Nelson.
So when you use an instruction to
think of giving instructions
to another person,
say someone that's smart but doesn't know
the specifics of your task.
So when it doesn't work, sometimes it's
because the instructions
weren't clear enough.
For example, if you were to say, Please
write me something about Alan Turing.
Well, in addition to that,
it can be helpful to be clear
about whether you want the text
to focus on his scientific work
or his personal life
or his role in history or something else.
And if you specify what you want
the tone of the text to be shouldn't
take on a tone like a professional
journalists were right?
Or is it more of a casual note
that you dash off to a friend
that hopes to generate what you want?
And of course, if you picture yourself
asking, see a fresh college graduate
to carry out this task for you,
if you can even specify
what snippets of texts
they should read in advance to write
this text about Alan Turing,
then that even better sets up
that fresh college track for success
to carry out this task for you.
So in the next video you see examples
of how to be clear and specific,
which is an important
principle of prompting ohms.
And you also learned from either
a second principle of prompting
that is giving a little time to think so
that let's go on to the next video.