There's so much sex in today's world,
pretty much
none of us have enough time to read
all the things we wish we had time to.
So one of the most exciting applications
I've seen of large
language models,
this is use it to summarize text.
And this is something that I'm seeing
multiple teams
built into multiple software applications.
You can do this in the chat
GBC web interface.
I do this all the time to summarize
articles, so I can just kind of read
the content of many will articles
in my previous to code.
And you want to do this
more programmatically.
You'll see how to in this lesson
so that let's take in the code
to see how you can use this yourself
to summarize sex.
So let's start off with the same article
as you saw before of import over there.
I know the API key
and here's that completion helper function
I'm going to use as the running example.
The task of summarizing
this product review got suspended
last week for a daughter's birthday
who loves it and takes it everywhere.
And so on and so on.
If you're building an e-commerce website
and there's
just a large volume of reviews,
having a tool to summarize
the lengthy reviews could give you a way
to very quickly glance over more reviews
to get a better sense
of what all your customers are thinking.
So here's a prompt
for generating a summary.
Your task is generated.
Short summary of our probably review
from e-commerce website.
Summarize review below and so on.
In that most three words
and so this is something cute
panda plush toys that buy daughter bismol
for the price arrive early.
Oh that's pretty good summary
and as you saw in the previous video
you can also play with things
like controlling the character count
or the number of sentences
to affect the length of this summary.
Now, sometimes when creating a summary,
if you have a very specific purpose
in mind for the summary, for example,
if you want to give feedback
to the shipping department,
you can also modify the prompt
to reflect that so that it can generate
a summary that is more applicable
to one particular group in your business.
So for example, if I adds to give feedback
to the
shipping
department that say I change this,
to tend to focus on
any aspects that mention
shipping and delivery of the product.
And if I run this, then
again you get a summary.
But instead of starting off
with something, you panned a plush toy.
It now focuses on the fact that it arrived
a day earlier than expected.
And then the store has other details that
or as another example,
if we aren't trying to give feedback
to the shipping department,
but let's say we want to give feedback
to the pricing department.
So the pricing department is
responsible for determining
the price of the product, and
I'm going to tell it to focus on
any aspects of relevance,
The price and perceived value.
Then this generates a different summary
that it says.
So maybe
the price may be too high for a size.
Now in the summary that I've generated
for the shipping department
or the pricing department, it focus a bit
more on information relevant
to those specific departments.
And in fact, feel free to pause the video
now and maybe ask it
to generate information
for the product department
responsible for the customer experience
of the product or for something else
that you think might be interesting
to an e-commerce site.
But in these summaries,
even though it generated information
relevant to shipping,
had some of the information
to which you could decide
may or may not be helpful.
So depending on
how you want to summarize it,
you can also ask it to extract information
rather than summarize it.
So here's a prompts
that says it has to extract relevant
information
to give feedback to shipping department.
And now it just says product arrives a day
earlier than expected
without all of the other information,
which was also helpful
in a general summary, but less specific
to the shipping department,
if I wants to know, is
what happened with the shipping.
Lastly, let me just
share with you a concrete example
for how to use this in a workflow to help
summarize multiple reviews
to make them easier to read.
So here are a few reviews.
This is kind of long, but here's
the second review for a seminar.
Neither from a bedroom.
His a review from a lecture Toothbrush.
My dental hygiene is recommended
kind of a long review
about the electric toothbrush.
This is a review from Blender
when they said sell said
17 piece system on seasonal sale and so on
and so on.
This is actually a longer tax.
If you want, feel free
to pause the video, visit all this text.
But what did you want to know
what these reviews wrote
without having to stop
and read all this in detail.
So I'm going to set review
one to be just a product review
that we had up there.
And I'm going to put all of these reviews
into a list.
And now if I implement a
full loop over the
reviews, So here's my prompt
and share of asset to summarize it
at most 20 words,
then let's have it
get the response
and print it out and let's run that
and it prints out
the first review asset and the toy review
summary, the review of the lamp,
some review of the toothbrush
and then the blender.
And so if you have
websites
where you have hundreds of reviews,
you can imagine how you might use this
to build a dashboard
to take huge numbers of reviews,
generally short summaries of them so that
you or someone else can browse
the reviews much more quickly.
And then if they wish, maybe click in
to see the original longer review.
And this can help you efficiently
get a better sense
of what
all of your customers are thinking.
Right?
So that's it for summarizing,
and I hope that you can picture
if you have any applications
with many pieces of text,
how you can use prompts like these
to summarize them, to help people quickly
get a sense of what's in the attacks,
the many pieces of text,
and perhaps optionally take in more
if they wish.
In the next video,
we'll look at another capability
of large language models,
which is to make inferences using texts.
For example,
what have you had a game product reviews
and you wanted to very quickly
get a sense of which product reviews
have a positive or negative sentiment.
Let's take a look at
how to do that in the next video.