Expanding as a torso, taking a shorter
piece of text
such as a set of instructions
or a list of topics,
and having the large language model
generate a longer
piece of text such as an email
or an essay about some topic.
There are some great uses of this, such
as if you use the large language model
as a brainstorming partner.
But I just also want acknowledge
that there's some problematic use cases
of this, such as if someone with a user
to generate a large amount of spam.
So when you use these capabilities
of a large language model,
please use it only in a responsible way
and in a way that helps people.
In this video, we'll go through an example
of how you can use a language model
to generate a personalized email
based on some information.
The email is kind of self
proclaimed to be from an AI bot,
which as I mentioned, is very important.
What else are you going to use?
Another one of the models
input parameters called temperature,
and this kind of allows you to vary
the kind of degree of exploration
and variety
in the kind of models responses.
So let's get into it.
So before we get started,
we're going to kind of do the usual setup.
So set up the open Python package
and then also define our helper
function, get completion.
And now we're
going to write a custom
email response to a customer review.
And so given a customer view
and the sentiment,
we're going to generate a custom response.
Now we're going to use the language model
to generate a custom email to a customer
based on a customer review
and the sentiment of the review.
So we've already extracted the sentiment
using
the kind of prompts that we saw
in the empowering video.
And then this is the customer
review for a blunder.
And now we're going to customize
the reply based on the sentiment.
And so here the instruction is
your you are our customer
service assistant.
Your task is to send an email reply
to a valued customer.
Given the customer
email is limited by three back to generate
a reply
to thank the customer for that review.
If the sentiment is positive or neutral,
thank them for that review.
If the sentiment is negative, apologize
and suggest that they can reach out
to customer service.
Make sure to use specific details
from the review.
Write in a concise and professional tone
and sign the email as a customer agent.
And when you're using a language model
to generate text that you're going to show
to a user, it's very important
to have this kind of transparency
and let the user know that
the text they're seeing was generated by,
and then we'll just input the customer
review and the review sentiment.
And also note
that this isn't necessarily important
because we could actually use this prompt
to also extract the review sentiment.
And then in a follow up
step, write the email.
But just for the sake of the example,
well,
we've already extracted the
sentiment from the review.
And so
here we have a response
to the customer addresses,
details that the customer mentioned
in their review
and kind of, as we instructed suggest
that they reach out to customer service
because this is just an air customer
service agent.
Next, we're going to use a parameter
of the language
model called temperature
that will allow us to
change the kind of variety
of the model's responses
so you can kind of think of temperature
as the degree of expiration
or kind of randomness of the model.
And so for this particular phrase,
my favorite food is
the kind of most likely next word
that the model predicts is pizza
and the kind of next to most likely
suggests are sushi and tacos.
And so at a temperature of zero,
the model will always choose
the most likely next word,
which in this case is pizza.
And at a higher temperature, it will also
choose one of the less likely words
and even at an even higher temperature,
it might even choose tacos,
which only kind of has
a 5% chance of being chosen.
And you can imagine that kind
of as the model continues,
this final response.
So my favorite food is pizza, and it kind
of continues to generate more words.
This response will kind of diverge
from the response.
The first response,
which is my favorite food, is tacos.
And so as a kind of model continues,
these two responses will become more
and more different.
In general, when building applications
where you want
a predictable response,
I would recommend using temperature zero.
Throughout all of these videos,
we've been using temperature zero.
And I think that if you're trying
to build a system
that is reliable and predictable,
you should go with this.
If you're trying to use the model
in a more creative way
where you might want a kind of wider
variety of different outputs,
you might want to use
a higher temperature.
So now let's take this same prompt
that we just used
and let's try generating an email,
but let's use a higher temperature.
So in our get completion function
that we've been using
throughout the videos,
we have kind of specified a model
and then also a temperature,
but we've kind of set them to default.
So now let's try burying the temperature.
So we use the prompt and then
let's try a
temperature 0.7.
And so with temperature zero,
every time you execute the same prompt,
you should expect the same completion.
Whereas with the temperature 0.7, you will
get a different output every time.
So here we have
email and as you can see, it's different
to the email that we kind of received
previously and let's just execute it again
to show
that we'll get a different email again.
And here we have another different email.
So I recommend that you kind of play
around with temperature yourself.
Maybe you could pause the video now
and try this prompt
with a variety of different temperatures
just to see how the outputs vary.
So to summarize
at higher temperatures, the outputs from
the model are kind of more random.
You can almost think of it
as at higher temperatures.
The assistant is more distractible
but maybe more creative.
In the next
video, we're going to talk more
about the chart completions and format
and how you can create a custom
chat bot using this format.