Las Vegas models are very good
at transforming
as input to a different format, such as
inputting a piece of text in one language
and transforming it,
or translating it to a different language
or helping with spelling
and grammar correction.
So taking this input, the piece of text
that may not be fully grammatical
and helping you to fix that up a bit,
or even transforming formats
such as inputting HTML and opposing JSON.
So there's a bunch of applications
that I used to write somewhat painfully
with a bunch of regular expressions
that would definitely
be much more simply implemented
now with a large language.
And although in a few prompts,
yeah, I used to GPT to proofread
pretty much everything I write these days.
So I'm excited to show you
some more examples in the notebook now.
So first we'll
import
openai and also use the same completion
helper function that we've been using
throughout the videos.
And the first thing we'll do
is a translation task.
So large language
models are trained on a lot of text
from kind of many sources,
a lot of which is the Internet.
And this is kind of,
of course, in many different languages.
So this kind of imbues the model
with the ability to do translation.
And these models know
kind of hundreds of languages
to varying degrees of proficiency.
And so we'll go through some examples
of how to use this capability.
So let's start off with something simple.
So in this first example,
the prompt is translate
the following English text to Spanish.
Hi, I would like to order a blender
and the response is allow me
goose diarrhea
or then a liquid quadra.
And I'm very sorry to all of you
Spanish speakers.
I never learn Spanish,
unfortunately, as you can definitely tell.
Okay, let's try another example.
So in this example,
the prompt is
tell me what language this is.
And then this is in French
Colombian food lump of death
and say let's from this.
And the model has identified
that this is French.
The model can also do
multiple translations at once.
So in this example, let's say translate
the following text to French and Spanish.
And you know what?
Let's add another and English
pirates.
The text is I want to order a basketball.
So here we have French, Spanish
and English pirates.
So in some languages
the translation can change
depending on the speaker's relationship
to the listener.
And you can also explain this
to the language model,
and it will be able to kind of
translate it accordingly.
So in this example,
we say translate the following text
to Spanish
in both the formal and informal forms.
Would you like to order a pillow
and also notice here
we're using a different delimiter
than these back texts.
It doesn't really matter as long as it's
kind of a clear separation.
So here we have the formal and informal.
So informal as when you're speaking
to someone who's maybe senior to you
or you're in a professional situation,
that's when you use a formal tone.
And then informal is when you're speaking
to maybe a group of friends.
I don't actually speak Spanish, but my dad
does, and he says that this is correct.
So for the next example,
we're going to pretend
that we're in charge
of a multinational e-commerce company.
And so the user messages are going to be
in all different languages.
And so users are going to be telling us
about the issues
in a wide variety of languages.
So we need a universal translator.
So first we'll just paste
in a list of user messages
in a variety of different languages.
And now we will loop through
each of these user messages.
So for issue and user messages,
and then I'm going to copy
over the slightly longer code block.
And so the first thing we'll do
is ask the model
to tell us what language the issue is in.
So here's the prompt.
Then we'll print out the original
messages, language and the issue,
and then we'll ask the model
to translate it into English and Korean.
So that's from this.
So the original message in French,
so we have a variety of languages
and then the model translates them
into English and then Korean
and you can kind of see here.
So the model says this is French.
So that's because the response from this
prompt is going to be, this is French.
You could try editing this prompt
to say something like,
Tell me what language this is.
Respond with only one
with only one word, or
don't use a sentence, that kind of thing.
If you wanted this to just be one word,
or you could ask for it in a Jason format
or something like that,
which would probably encourage it
to not use a whole sentence.
And so amazing.
You've just built a universal translator.
And also feel free to pause the video
and add kind of any other languages
you want to try here.
Maybe languages you speak your self
and see how the model does.
So the next thing we're going to dive
into is tone transformation.
Writing can vary
based on an intended audience.
You know the way that I would write
an email to a colleague or a professor
is obviously going to be quite different
to the way I text my younger brother.
And so interactivity can actually
also help produce different tones.
So let's look at some examples.
So in this first example,
the prompt is translate the following
from slang to a business letter.
Dude, this is Joe.
Check out the spec on the standing lamp.
So let's execute this.
And as you can see,
we have a much more formal business letter
with a proposal for a standing lamp
specification.
The next thing that we're going to do
is to convert between different formats.
GBC is very good at translating
between different formats such as JSON to
HTML, XML, all kinds of things, markdown.
And so in the
prompt will describe both the input
and the output formats.
So here is an example.
So we have this JSON that contains
a list of restaurant employees
with their name and email.
And then in the prompt,
we're going to ask the model
to translate this from JSON to its HTML.
So the prompt is translate
the following Python dictionary from JSON
to an HTML table
with column headers and titles,
and then we'll get the response
from the model and print it.
So here we have some HTML displaying
all of the employee names and emails.
And so now let's
see if we can actually view this HTML.
So we're going to use this
display function from this Python library
display HTML response.
And here you can see that
this is a properly formatted
HTML table.
The next transformation task we're going
to do is spell check and grammar checking.
And this is a really kind of popular
use for GPT.
I highly recommend doing this.
I do this all the time
and it's especially useful
when you're walking
in a non-native language.
And so here are some examples
of some common grammar
and spelling problems and how the language
model can help address these.
So I'm going to paste in a list of
sentences that have some grammatical
or spelling errors,
and then we're going to
loop through each of these sentences
and ask the model to proofread these
proofread and correct,
and then we'll use some delimiter limiters
and then we will get the response
and print it as usual.
And so the model is able to correct
all of these grammatical errors,
and we could use some of the techniques
that we've discussed before.
So we could to improve the prompt.
We can say proofreading, correct
the following text
and rewrite
and rewrite the whole
and rewrite it,
corrected
version.
If you don't find any errors,
just say
no errors.
Found.
Let's try this.
So this way
we were able to still using quotes here,
but you can imagine
you'd be able to find a way
with a little bit of iterative
prompt development
to kind of find a problem that works
more reliably every single time.
And so now we'll do another example.
It's always useful to check your text
before you post it in a public forum.
And so we'll go through an example
of checking a review.
And so here is a review
about a stuffed panda.
And so we're going to ask the model
to proofread and correct the review.
Great.
So we have this corrected version, and one
cool thing we can do is find the kind
of differences between our original review
and the model's output.
So we're going to use this red lines
Python package to do this,
and we're going to get the diff
between the original
text of our review and the model output
and then display this.
And so here you can see the difference
between the original review and
the model output and the kind of things
that have been corrected.
So the prompt that we use was proofread
and correct this review, but you can also
make kind of more dramatic changes,
changes to tone and that kind of thing.
So let's try one more thing.
So in this prompt,
we're going to ask the model to proofread
and correct this same review,
but also make it more compelling
and ensure that it follows
APA style and targets an advanced reader.
And we're also going to ask
for the output in markdown format.
And so we're using the same text
from the original review up here.
So let's execute this.
And here we have a expanded
APA style review of the soft panda.
So this is it for the transforming video.
Next up, we have expanding where
we'll take a shorter prompt
and kind of generate a longer, more free
form response from a language model.