This next video is on inferring.
I like to think of these tasks
where the model takes
a Texas input and performs
some kind of analysis.
So this could be extracting
labels, extracting names,
kind of understanding the sentiment
of a text, that kind of thing.
So if you want to extract the sentiment,
positive or negative of a piece of text
in the traditional machine
learning workflow, you have to
collect a label dataset, train the model,
figure out how to deploy the model
some of the call and make inferences.
And that can work pretty well.
But it was just a lot of work
to go through that process.
And also every task such as sentiment
versus extracting means versus
something else, you have to train
and deploy a separate model.
One of the really nice things about large
language model
is that for me, tools like these,
you can just
write a prompt and have a site
generating results pretty much right away.
And that gives tremendous speed
in terms of applications development.
And you can also just use one model,
one API to do many different tasks
rather than needing
to figure out how to train
and deploy a lot of different models.
And so with that,
let's jump into the code
to see how you can take advantage of this.
So here's a usual starter code.
I'll just run that.
And the most vivid example
I'm going to use is a review for a lamp.
So neither the nice lamp for the bedroom
and this one additional
storage and so on. So
let me write a prompt
to classify the sentiments of this
and if I want the system to tell me,
you know what this is, sentiments
I can just write.
What is the sentiment
of the following
product review
with the usual delimiter
or the review text
and so on, and thus run that
and assess a section of the project
Review is positive,
which is actually seems pretty right
to slap isn't perfect,
but this customer seems pretty happy
since they're a great company
that cares about the customers
and products.
I think positive sentiment
seems like the right answer.
Now this turns out the entire sentence is
sent from the product review is positive.
If you wanted to give a more concise
response
to make it easier for post-processing,
I can take this prompt
and add another instruction
to give you adds as a single word,
either positive or negative.
So just prints are positive like this,
which makes it easier for a piece of text
to take this output
and process it and do something with it.
Let's look at another prompt again.
So using the lamp review
here I have it.
Identify a list of emotions.
So the rights of the following review
is expressing,
including one in five items in this list.
So launch language models are pretty good
at extracting specific things
out of a piece of text.
In this case, were expressing the emotions
and this could be useful
for understanding how your customers
think about the particular products
from other customer support organizations.
Is important to understand
if a particular user is extremely upset.
So you might have a different
classification problem.
Like this is the rights of the fight
review expressing anger
because if someone is really angry,
it might merits paying extra attention
to have a customer review, to have
customer support and customer success,
reach out to figure what's going on
and make things right for the customer.
In this case, the customer is not angry
and notice that with supervised learning,
if I had wanted to build
all of these classifiers, this
no way, you know, I would have been able
to do this with supervised learning in the
just a few minutes that you saw me do.
So in this video,
I encourage you to pause this video
and try changing some of these prompts.
Maybe also, if the customer is expressing
delight, will ask
if there are any missing parts
and see if you can get a prompt
to make different inferences about this.
That review.
Let me show you some more things
that you can do with this system,
specifically extracting
richer information from a customer review.
So information extraction is the positive
and help of natural language processing
that relates to taking a piece of text
and extracting certain things
that you want to know from detects.
So it does prompt asking.
It identified the following items,
the item
purchase and the name of the company
that made the item.
Again, if you are trying to summarize
many reviews
from an online
shopping e-commerce website,
it might be useful for your lost
collection of reviews
to figure out what were the items
who made the item figure a positive
or negative sentiment to track trends
about positive or negative sentiment
for specific items
or for specific manufacturers.
And in this example, I'm going to ask it
to format your response as a Jason object
with item and brand as a keys.
And so if I do that, it says
the items are that the brands
this luminaire and you can easily notice
into the python dictionary on to then
do additional processing on this output
in these apples have gone through
you saw how to write a prompt
to recognize the sentiment, figure out
if someone is angry,
and then also
extract the item and to brand
one way to extract all of this information
would be to use three or four Trumps.
And Cole did completion,
you know, three times or four times.
Extract these different views
one at a time.
But it turns out you can actually write
a single prompt
to extract all this information
at the same time.
So the say, identify the following items.
Extra sentiment is a reviewer expressing
anger item purchase company that made it
and then here
I'm also going to tow it to formats
the anchor value as a as a proven value.
And then we run that
and this opens a on Jason
where sentence is positive anger
and in no quotes are false
because it also it's
just up as a proof of value.
They extracted the item a slap of additional storage and so the lamp seems okay.
But this
way you can extract multiple fields
out of a piece of text
with just a single prompt.
And as usual, please feel free to pause
a video and play with different variations
of this yourself.
Or maybe even try typing in
a totally different review to see
if you can still extract these things
accurately.
Now, one of the coup applications
I've seen of large
language models is in three topics.
Given the long piece of text, you know,
what is this piece of text about?
What are the topics?
Here's a fictitious newspaper
article about how government workers
see about the agency they work for.
So the recent survey
conducted by government
and so on, the results of euthanasia
was a popular department
with high satisfaction rating.
I am a fan and also love the work they do,
but this is a fictitious article
and so given an article
like this, we can ask it
with this prompt
determine five topics
that are being discussed in the following
texts.
This. NICKISCH Item one or two.
As long for my response
to that comma separated lists.
And so if we run, that's
you know, we get out this article
is about covering surveys
by job satisfaction and also and so on.
So overall, I think pretty nice
of extraction of a list of topics.
And of course you can also, you know,
split it so you get a Python list
with the five topics
that this article was about.
And if you have a collection of articles
and extract topics, you could
then also use the large nitish model
to help you index into different topics.
So let me use a slightly different
topic lists that say that
we're a news website or something
and you know,
these are the topics
we try and also local government
engineering, employee satisfaction,
federal governments.
And let's say you want to figure out,
given the news article,
which of these topics are
covered in that news article.
So here's a prompt that I can use.
I'm going to say determine
whether each item
the following list of topics
is a topic in the text below
give you answers,
and this is a URL one for each topic.
And so oh
great, so does it.
Same story. Texas to four.
So this thing's a story.
It is about Nasser.
It's not about local governments,
not about injury.
It is about employees, how the statute
than it is about federal government.
So with this in machine learning,
this is sometimes called a zero shot
learning
algorithm because we didn't give it
any training data that was labeled.
So that's zero shot.
And with just a prompt,
it was able to determine
which of these topics are covered
in that news article.
And so if you want to generate
news alert, say so that process news
and you know,
I really like a lot of words and also does
so if you want to build a system
that can take this you know,
put this information into a dictionary
and whenever Nasser News pops up
in a story,
they can use this to very quickly
take the article, figure out what topics
it is about, and if the topic includes
and also have a printout of their it's
new analysis story.
Oh, just one thing.
I use this topic to take a dictionary down
here.
This prompt that I use up here
isn't very robust.
If I want to the production system,
I would probably have it.
I'll put the answer as a
SO in Jason format rather than as a list,
because the output of the like this model
can be a little bit inconsistent.
So this is actually
a pretty brutal piece of code.
But if you once when you're done
watching this video, feel free to see
if you can figure out how to modify
this prompt to have it output.
Jason instead of a list like this
and then have a more robust way to tell
if a particular article
is a story about Nasser.
So that's it for inferring.
And in just a few minutes you can build
multiple systems for making inferences
about texts that precede.
This is a chicken days or even weeks
for a skilled machine learning developer.
And so I find this very exciting that
both the skilled machine
learning developers as well as for people
that are newer to machine learning,
you can now choose protein.
It's a very quickly build
and start making inferences
on pretty complicated natural language
processing tasks like these.
In the next video, we'll continue
to talk about exciting things you could do
if large language models
ever go on to transforming
how you take one piece of text
and transform it
into a different piece of text,
such as translated to different language.
Let's go on to the next video.