One of the exciting
things about the launch language model is
you could use it to build a custom chat
bot with only a modest amount of effort.
Chad GPT
The web interface is a way for you
to have a conversational interface,
a conversation via a large language model.
But one of the cool things is
you can also use a large language model
to build your custom chat
bot to maybe play the role of a customer
service agent or an A.I.,
or to take over restaurants.
And as video,
you learn how to do that for yourself.
I'm going to describe the components
of the open completions format
in more detail, and then you're going
to build a chatbot yourself.
So let's get into it.
So first will set up the opening
python package as usual.
So chat models like GBG
are actually trained to take a series
of messages as input and return
a model generated message as output.
And so
although the chat format is designed
to make multichannel conversations
like this easy, we've kind of seen
through the previous videos that it's
also just as useful for singleton tasks
without any conversation.
And so next we're going to define
to help the functions.
So this is the one that we've been using
throughout all the videos,
and it's the completion function.
But if you kind of look at it,
we give a prompt.
But then inside the function,
what we're actually doing is putting
this prompt into what
looks like some kind of user message.
And this is because
the chat CBT model is a chat model,
which means it's trained
to take a series of messages as input
and then return a model
generated messages output.
So the user message is the input, and
then the assistant message is the output.
So in this
video, we're going to actually use
a different helper function
and instead of kind of putting
a single prompt as input
and getting a single completion,
we're going to pass in a list of messages.
And these messages can be kind of
from a variety of different roles.
So I'll describe those.
So here's
an example of a list of messages.
And so the first message
is a system message, which kind of gives
an overall instruction.
And then after this message, we have tons
between the user and the assistant.
And this is kind of continue to go on.
And if you've ever used Chartbeat,
the Web interface, then you your messages
of the user messages and then chat
gets messages of the assistant messages.
So the system message helps
to kind of set the behavior
and persona of the assistant,
and it acts as kind of a high level
instruction for the conversation.
So you can kind of think of it
as whispering in the assistants ear
and kind of guiding it to responses
without the use of being aware
of the system message.
So as the user, if you've ever used you,
you probably don't know
what's in the system message.
The benefit of the system
method is that it
provides you, the developer, with a way
to kind of frame the conversation
without making the request itself
part of the conversation.
So you can kind of guide the assistant
and kind of whisper in its ear
and guide its responses
without making the user aware.
So now let's try to use these
messages in a conversation.
So we'll use our new helper function
to get the completion
from the messages
and what will say
using a higher temperature.
So the system message says you are
an assistant that speaks like Shakespeare.
So this is us kind of describing
to the assistant how it should behave.
And then the first user messages
tell me a joke.
The next is
why did the chicken cross the road?
And then the final user message is,
I don't know.
So if we run this,
the response is to get to the other side.
Let's try again
to get to the other side first from Adam.
Tis an old and classic that never fails.
So that's our Shakespearean response.
And that's actually try one more thing,
because I want to make it even clearer
that this is the assistant message.
So here, let's just go and print the
the entire
message response.
So just to make this even clearer, this
response is an assistant message.
So the role is assistant and
then the content is the message itself.
So that's what's happening in this helper
function, which is kind of passing out
the content of the message.
So now let's do another example.
So here our messages are
this is the message
is your friendly chat bot
and the first user messages.
Hi, my name is Isa and we want to
get the first user message,
so let's execute this.
So the first assistant message
and so the first messages.
Hello, It's nice to meet you.
How can I assist you today?
Now let's try another example.
So here on message is our system Message
your friendly chat bot
and the first user messages. Yes.
Can can you remind me what is my name?
And let's get the response.
And as you can see,
the model doesn't actually know my name.
So each conversation with a language
model is a standalone interaction,
which means that you must provide
all relevant messages for the model
to draw from in the current conversation.
If you want the model to draw from
or quote unquote remember
earlier parts of the conversation,
you must provide the earlier exchanges
in the input to the model.
And so we refer to this as context.
So let's try this.
So now we've kind of given
the contacts that the model needs,
which is my name
and the previous messages,
and we'll ask the same question.
So we'll ask what my name is.
And the model is able to respond because
it has all of the contacts it needs.
And this kind of list of
messages that we input to it.
So now
you're going to build your own chat bot.
This chat bot is going to be called
order bot
and we're going to automate the collection
of user prompts and assistant responses
in order to build this order bots.
And it's going to take orders
at a pizza restaurant.
So first we're going to define
this helper function.
And what this is doing is it's going
to kind of collect our user messages
so we can avoid typing them in by hand
in the same in the way that we did above.
And this is going to kind of collect
prompts from a user interface
that will build below and then append it
to a list called context.
And then it will call the model
with that context every time.
And the model response is
then also added to the contact.
So the kind of model message
is added to the context, the user message
is added to the context, so on.
So it just kind
of grows longer and longer.
This way the
model has the information
it needs to determine what to do next.
And so now we'll set up and run
this kind of UI to display the order bots.
And so here's the context, and it contains
the system message that contains the menu
and note that every time we call
the language model,
we're going to use the same context.
And the context is building up over time.
And then let's execute
this.
Okay, I'm going to say hi,
I would like to order a pizza.
And the assistant says, Great,
What pizza would you like to order?
We have pepperoni, cheese and eggplant
pizza.
Hmm. How much are they?
Great.
Okay, we have the prices
and think I'm feeling a medium
eggplant pizza.
So, as you can imagine,
we could continue this conversation,
and let's kind of
look at what we put in the system message.
So you are all about an automated service
to collect orders for a pizza restaurant.
You first greet
the customer, then collect the order,
and then ask
if it's a pick up or delivery.
You wait to collect the entire order, then
summarize it and check for a final time.
If the customer wants to add
anything else.
If it's a delivery,
you can ask for an address.
Finally, you collect the payment.
Make sure to clarify all options,
extras and sizes to uniquely identify
the item from the menu.
You respond in a short,
very conversational, friendly style.
The menu includes.
And then here we have the menu.
So let's go back to our conversation
and let's see if the assistant kind of
has been following the instructions.
Okay, great.
The assistant asks
if we want any toppings,
which we kind of specified
in the system message.
So I think we want no extra toppings.
Sure thing.
Is there anything else we'd like to order?
Mm. Let's get some water.
Actually.
Fries, small or large.
And this is great because we kind of
off the assistant in the system message
to kind of
clarify access and sides.
So and so you get the idea.
And please feel free to play with this
yourself.
You can pause the video
and just go ahead and run this in your own
notebook on the left.
And so now we can ask the model
to create a JSON summary
that we could send to the order system
based on the conversation.
So we're now
appending another system message,
which is an instruction,
and we're saying create a JSON
summary of the previous food
order, itemized the price for each item.
The fields should be one.
Pizza includes side
two list
of toppings, three lists of drinks
and four list of sides
and finally the total price.
And you could also
use a user message here.
This does not have to be a system message.
So let's execute this.
And notice in this case,
we're using a lower temperature
because for these kinds of tasks, we want
the output to be fairly predictable.
For a conversational agent, you might want
to use a higher temperature.
However, in this case I would maybe use
a lower temperature as well,
because for a customer assistant
shop, what you might want the output to be
to be a bit more predictable as well.
And so here
we have the summary of our order
and so we could submit this to the
the order system if we wanted to
so that we have it.
You've built your variant order chapbook.
Feel free to kind of customize it yourself
and play around with the system message
to change the behavior of the chop bar
and kind of
get it to act as different personas
with different knowledge.