Congratulations on
making it to the end of this short course.
In summary, in this short course,
you'll learn
about two key principles
for prompting, right?
Clear and specific instructions
and when it's appropriate,
give them all the time to think.
You also learn
about iterative prompt development and how
having a process to get to the prompt
is right for your application is key.
And we went through a few capabilities
of large language models
that are useful for many applications,
specifically summarizing
and very transforming and expanding.
And you also saw
how to build a custom chat bot
that wasn't lost that you learned
in just one short course.
And I hope you enjoyed
going through these materials.
We hope you'll come up with some ideas
for applications
that you can build yourself.
Now please go try this out
and let us know what you come up with.
No application is too small.
It's fine to start with something
that's kind of a very small project
with maybe a little bit of utility,
or maybe it's not even useful at all.
It's just something fun.
Yeah.
And I find playing with these models
actually really fun.
So go play with it.
Yeah, I agree. It's a good weekend
activity.
Speaking from experience.
Oh, and just, you know, please
use the learnings from your first project
to build about a second project
and maybe even about a third project.
So on.
That's
kind of how I have kind of grown over time
using these models myself as well.
Or if
you have an idea for a bigger
project already, just just go for it
and you know, as a reminder,
these kind of large language
models are a very powerful technology.
So it kind of goes without saying
that we ask you to use them responsibly
and please only build things
that will have a positive impact.
Yeah, I fully agree.
I think in this age, people that built
the AI systems can have a huge impact
on others.
So small, important than ever
that all of us only use these tools
responsibly.
And I think building large language
model based
applications is just a very exciting
and growing field right now.
And now that you've finished this course,
I think you now have a wealth
of knowledge to let you build things
that few people today know how to.
So I hope you also help us
to spread the word and encourage others
to take this course, too.
In closing, I hope you had fun during this
course and I want to thank you
for finishing this course
and both Ethan, I look forward to hearing
about the amazing things that you feel.